host.in 2013-09-20

# Privacy Policy

Host.in is committed to protecting the privacy of our clients and users of this website. This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Host.in uses, maintains and discloses information collected from its clients and users of its website.

## 1\. Commitment to your Privacy

We collect the bare minimum amount of information about you, to allow us to provide you with a satisfactory service. This Policy indicates the type of processes that may result in data being collected about you. The purpose of this Privacy Policy to enable you to understand which personal identifying information ("PII", "Personal Information") of yours is collected, how and when we might use your information, who has access to this information, and how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

## 2\. Information Collected

We may collect any or all of the information via both automated means such as communications profiles and cookies. Personal Information you give us depends on the type of service, support, or sale inqury, and may include your name, address, telephone number, fax number and email address, dates of service provided, types of service provided, payment history, manner of payment, amount of payments, date of payments, domain name, credit card or other payment information. The financial information will be transferred only be used to bill you for the products and services you purchased. If you purchase by credit card, this information may be forwarded to your credit card provider. All sensitive information is collected on a secure server and data is transferred. When transferring personal information a security icon will appear in your browser.

## 3\. Information Use

This information is used for billing and to provide service and support to our clients. We may also review this information to determine our clients needs and provide support for our clients. All reasonable precautions are taken to prevent unauthorised access to this information. This safeguard may require you to provide additional forms of identity should you wish to obtain information about your account details. Host.in may email its monthly newsletter to the primary contact e-mail on file, but clients are able to opt out of this newsletter at any time.

## 4\. Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer our site and servers, track access, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. It is possible that personal information about a client may be included in the log files due to the normal functions of IP addresses and Web browsing.

## 5\. Cookies

Your Internet browser has the in-built facility for storing small text files called cookies, that hold information which allows a website to recognize your account. We use cookies to save your preferences and login information, and provide personalized functionality. You can reject cookies by changing your browser settings, but be aware that this will disable some of the functionality on the Host.in's website. Click [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) to find more information about cookies.

## 6\. Disclosing Information

We do not disclose any personal information obtained about you from this website to third parties. This does not apply to affiliates that provide services to you based on links provided within your CPanel access and control, wherein information will be shared to facilitate your use of additional amenities included with your hosting account We may use personal information to keep in contact with you and inform you of developments associated with our business. We may also disclose aggregate, anonymous data based on information collected from users to potential partners, our affiliates, and reputable third parties. We take all available measures to select affiliates and service providers that are ethical and provide similar privacy protection to their clients and the community. We do not make any representations about the practices and policies about these companies.

## 7\. Correcting/Updating Personal Information

If a client's personally identifiable information changes, or if a client no longer desires our services, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that client's personal data in our records. In most cases, this can be achieved via the [Client Area](https://www.host.in/manage/clientarea.php). Otherwise, please contact us at sales@host.in.

## 8\. Opt Out & Modifications

By default, clients do receive any voluntary system updates, such as the newsletters, invoices, and mailings. Any client who voluntarily receives these updates may unsubscribe at any time. Clients may not opt out of possibly receiving important system notifications, in the rare event that such notification would be necessary.

## 9\. Security

Host.in uses technical security measures to prevent the loss, misuse, alternation or unauthorized disclosure of information under our control. Host.in uses security measures including and not limited to: physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. When we ask clients or users to provide financial information (such as a credit card number) that data is protected using Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL") technology.

## 10\. Data and Information Submitted to Another Person or Entity on Our Network

As mentioned above, Host.in collects certain data and confidential information from clients relating to our web site hosting and domain name registration services, and this Privacy Policy applies only to that data and confidential information submitted to us.

## 11\. Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about Clients upon valid request by government or law officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including without limitation subpoenas), to protect your property and rights, or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or stop activity we consider illegal or unethical.

## 12\. Changes to this Policy

Any changes to our Privacy Policy will be placed here and will supersede this version of our Policy. We will take reasonable steps to draw your attention to any changes in our Policy. However, we recommend that you read this document each time you use the website to ensure that it still meets with your approval.

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, or if you want to know what information we have collected about you, please email us at privacy@host.in. You can also correct any factual errors in that information or require us to remove your details from any list under our control, by emailing the above mentioned email address.
